Guide to the Daniel Willard Fiske papers, 1847-1927, 1847-1904 (bulk)
Fiske, Daniel Willard papers, 1847-1927, 1847-1904 (bulk)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Documents and Memorabilia
  - Fiske's will and obituary (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 57)
  - Library Journal obituary (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 59)
  - English obituaries (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 60)
  - Italian obituaries (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 61)
  - Scrapbook (Box 13-1-348: 20)
  - CW Fiske's notebook, 1895 (Box 13-1-348: 20)
  - Bibliography notebook (Box 13-1-348: 20)
  - McGraw and Fiske Estates books (Box 13-1-348: 21-23)
  - Fiske/McGraw marriage certificate, July 13, 1880 (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper articles on Fiske, Date unknown (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 10)
  - Archaic lettered stone (Box 13-1-348: 27)
  - Fiske Library Fund papers, 1911-1917 (Box 13-1-28: 1)
- Series VII. Photographs
  - Subseries VIIa. Photographs from Egypt
    These are commercial photographs, some from Abdullah Freres, JP Sebah, A. Beato, and Bonfils among others.
    - Willard Fiske's "Passport to visit the Egyptian Antiquities,", 1889-06-30 (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 1)
    - Photochroms, 8x10 in
    - Pyramids and Menahouse Hotel (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 7)
    - The Pyramid at Sakkara (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 7)
    - Shepheard's Hotel, Cairo (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 7)
    - Mosque of Sultan Hassan, Cairo (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 7)
    - The Pavilion at Medinet-Abou, Thebes (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 7)
    - The Port, Port Said (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 7)
    - Albumen prints, 8x10 in
    - Human Interest: Arab shops in old Cairo, woman and children on donkey, women with stone jars, camels, camels with drivers, donkeys with driver, buffalo, ostriches, date palms, old fort and palms, street procession and crowd scene. (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 8)
    - Pyramids and the Sphinx: Sphinx, ascending the pyramid, general view of the pyramids (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 9)
    - Al-Azhar (Arab University): entrance, doorway, courtyard, minarets, cloisters with students, students in courtyard (Box 13-1-1165: 18)
    - Temple at Luxor: Columns, statue of woman, exterior view with date palm (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 11)
    - Buildings in or near Cairo: Arab village, L'Esbekieh (Square with horse-drawn cabs), general view of a dam, Verandah at Shepherd's Hotel Sanctuary of a Mosque, Interior dome of a Mosque, Building partly in ruins, Riverside with fort and date palms, Place de l'Opera, Cairo, Street in Cairo, Palace Hotel, Cairo, Mosque of Sultan Hassan, Minarets, Gizah Bridge, Mosque and tomb of Kait-Bey, Tomb of the Califes and Cairo Citadel, Arab cemetery Unidentified building, New Hotel, Cairo, miscellaneous buildings (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 10)
    - Colossus: Rameses, two colossus of Memnon (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 12)
    - Friezes, statues, mummies, etc.: Giza mummies, monoliths and ships, seated figures, wooden statue, inscriptions, statues, statue of Chefron, tomb inscriptions (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 13)
    - Temples, tombs, etc.: Temple of Isis Philae, columns, Denderah temple, Temple of Rameses, Colon at Abydos, heads of columns, Obelisk, doorway and columns at Thebes, inscribed columns, Medinet-abou hypostyle of temple, ruins of temple (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 14)
    - Ruins of Karnak: general view, obelisks, interior doorway, wall with inscriptions, triumphal archway of Rameses IV, columns (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 15)
    - River scenes with boats: banks of the Nile, Nile with temple in the background, Nile with cruisers and sailboats river bank with Arabs working a type of derrick, dam across river (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 16)
    - Gardens and roads: Djezireh road, Schoubra road, garden of Ezbekieh, grotto, Antoniadwa III garden in Alexandria, Tree of St. Vierge, zoological garden. (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous: Palace of Gihezireh, window of mosque El Refai, courtyard of Arab house, view of Arab town (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 18)
    - Albumen prints, 4x6 in
    - Miscellaneous: road to Giza, lake, Arab town with minarets, doorway with colossus, bust of Cleopatra at Denderah, tomb of a caliph, Arab woman (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 18)
  - Subseries VIIb. Family, Friends and Travel
    - Photographs "Fiske's Studio, 3A, Via Lungo et Mugnone, Florence..." (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 6)
    - Cabinet card photographs of Villa Landor (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 3-4)
    - Portrait of Willard Fiske (Box 13-1-1165: 18, Folder 2)
    - Card photographs - Friends, relatives, Villa Landor, travel views (Box 13-1-1165: 20, Folder 1-41)
    - Portraits of Jennie McGraw Fiske, ca. 1880 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 1)
    - Bust of John McGraw cabinet cards (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 2)
    - Portraits of Daniel Willard Fiske, 1879-1904 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 3)
    - Portrait of Daniel Willard Fiske (Box 13-1-1165: ms box, Folder 1)
      Formerly on display in the A.D. White library
    - Portraits of Daniel Willard Fiske, 1880-1904 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 4)
    - Cabinet card photographs of Daniel Willard Fiske, some with Michele Monzecchi (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 5)
    - Portraits of Fiske in Egypt, ca. 1888-1889 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 6)
    - Fiske on board steamer, early Kodak prints, ca. 1890 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 7)
    - Fiske and the Stellas on board ship (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 8)
    - Unmounted collodion prints of the Villa Landor and Fiske (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 9)
    - Portraits of DH and CW Fiske, daguerreotypes, ca. 1850 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 10)
    - Three portraits by Schemboche of Florence (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 11)
    - Cabinet card portraits of CW Fiske (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 12)
    - Assorted family photos (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 13)
    - Hand painted frames with portraits of Fiske (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 14-15)
    - Metal frame with portrait of CW Fiske (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 16)
    - Michele Monzecchi portraits, with 'lessons' (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 17-18)
    - Photographs from CF Westbury, with letter, 1902 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 19)
    - Dr. and Mrs. Aksel Anderson, Upsala in his study (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 20)
    - Bjarni Jonsson (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 21)
    - Dr. Konrad Von Maurer (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 22)
    - Cabinet cards of the Villa Landor (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 23)
    - Fiske's Studio (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 24)
    - DW Fiske chess games (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 25)
    - Cabinet card portraits from Egypt, 1897 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 26)
    - Printed reproduction of artwork, Players at the first American chess congress, ca. 1857 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 27)
    - Campus scenes at Cornell University (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 28)
    - Torre de Gallo portraits, Florence by Fratelli Alinari (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 28a)
    - Cabinet card photographs of Lund, Sweden by Lina Jonn (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 29)
    - Cabinet card photographs of Upsala, Chateau de Chillon (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 30)
    - Printed scenes of Upsala, Sweden (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 31)
    - Photographic postcard of the Vatican library in Rome (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified sports team (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 33)
    - Photograph of Fiske memorial pillow (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 34)
    - Photograph reproductions of correspondence, 1832, 1877 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 35)
    - The villa Landor (Box 13-1-348: 20)
    - Portraits of Jennie McGraw Fiske (Box 13-1-348: 20)
    - Scenes from Sweden, Norway (Box 13-1-348: 20)
    - Unidentified interiors, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 1)
    - Unidentidied portraits, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 2)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm II saloon and ladies room, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 3)
    - Hand colored photographs of Italy, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 4)
    - Fontaine de Vaucluse, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified landscapes, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 6)
    - Montpelier, Avignon, and unidentified, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 7-8)
    - Vestmanlands Dala Nation in Upsala, 1900 (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 9)
    - McGraw-Fiske mansion, exterior photographs, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 11)
    - Tintype of men at Taughannock Falls, 1875 (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 12)
      George Hartt, Emmons Lee Williams, Josiah Williams, Daniel Willard Fiske
    - Mrs. Fiske, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 13)
    - Jennie McGraw Fiske and Daniel Willard Fiske on boat in Egypt during their honeymoon, 1880 (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 14)
    - Iceland, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 15)
    - Jennie McGraw Fiske medallion, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 16)
    - Jennie McGraw Fiske tomb in Sage Chapel, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 16)
    - Building interiors and exteriors, Undated (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 17)
    - Five carte-de-visite photograph albums originally belonging to Jennie McGraw Fiske (Box 13-1-348: 28)
    - Fiske's library at Villa Forini, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 1)
    - Trento, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 2)
    - Landscapes and people, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs by Somner.
    - Portraits, mostly unidentified, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 4)
    - Stockholm and Trollhatten, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 5)
    - Portraits, mostly unidentified, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 6)
    - Roman sites and art travel photographs, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 7)
    - Le Rigi Kulm, by Charnaux Freres, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 8)
    - Montpelier, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 9)
    - Snapshots of Fiske, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 10)
    - Firenze, Napoli, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 11)
    - Jennie McGraw Fiske, in ornate frame, Undated (Box 13-1-1165: 25)
- Series VIII. Card files
  - Visiting cards (of Fiske's callers) (Box 13-1-1165: 22-23)
- Series IX. Audio Material
  - "Willard Fiske and Chess", Stephen Weissman, TR-8042a (Box 13-1-1165: 24)
  - "Willard Fiske Runic Collection", Elmer H. Antonsen, TR-8043a (Box 13-1-1165: 24)
  - "Willard Fiske and Chess", Stephen Weissman, TR-8044a (Box 13-1-1165: 24)
  - "Willard Fiske Icelandic Collection", Phillip Marshal Mitchell, TR-8044a (Box 13-1-1165: 24)
  - "Willard Fiske and Cornell University", Gould Patchin Colman, TR-8045a (Box 13-1-1165: 24)
  - "Willard Fiske Rhaeto-Romanic Collection", Louis Pitschmann, TR-8046a (Box 13-1-1165: 24)